Tent Agenda. Staff recommends we remove line items four and five. Motion.
Second.
Hi.
Okay.
Williams.
Marker.
Hi.
One item seven.
No, some sorry six.
Action item budget amendment for moving capital improvement.
So when we just voted on.
Make motion.
Say it.
Hi.
Public hearing on submission of a grant application to the Oklahoma tourism and recreation department
division of state parks federal grant section for a trail around the splash pad complex.
This has my name on it, but I'm not sure that I know what I'm talking about.
There we go.
It's open.
Well, we are just here for the public forum part so that we can pursue a grant application.
And we'd like to have your approval for that.
We're doing a trail grant by the Oklahoma tourism and recreation department.
They were instrumental in funding the splash pad.
And now we'd like to see if we can get a grant from them to construct a trail that will wind its way around through the splash pad area over by Joe Pollock and tie into the tennis courts and the skate park.
Oh, what's the distance?
Do you know?
We're going to do a mile track.
So that way, it would also serve for the people that do fitness walking and we'll have signs up that mark like quarter miles.
Is it going to be as windy as the one over by India?
No.
Good.
It won't be.
We're working on a plan to get the Australians together.
Yeah.
That thing kills your knees.
Not walking probably so much, but running.
Have ran it a lot.
That's what I don't need.
Have run some difference.
If you run your run.
I don't know.
This is the age 20 grand.
Yes, sir.
What do you anticipate?
Awesome.
Well, right now we do have $150,000 budgeted that we can use.
The grant they will fund in the amount of $300,000.
So we're well within our limits with what we want to do.
We've got that money.
It's budgeted.
It's there.
Yes, sir.
They're cool.
So I know it's like the library did some cool stuff at the old rotary park loop.
There would be opportunities to do some of that stuff here where they had stations where kids could do learning.
Stay.
A little tie in really well with the outdoor learning environment that's going in right now.
So we'll have some inches placed.
We can do some natural floor and fun.
throughout, and future goals will be to put in some shade structures, as well as picnic areas,
so that, you know, this big complex can be enjoyed by everybody.
So, you don't have any designs like anything drawn up yet, you know, because it's just for the application.
So, I'm assuming at some point we'd see some kind of design, we'd be published and put out to the public.
Yes.
Perfect.
Is this, I don't think this is an axon, we don't need emotional, this is just the, okay, never mind.
It comes next.
I appreciate you guys.
I'm excited about where this part is going.
Absolutely.
Yeah, I appreciate you guys' efforts.
Thank you.
Please, I won't flood.
So, just bear.
Okay.
Yes.
You should ask if there's anybody else.
Right.
That's what, that was my next, my next action was,
is there any other public comments that anybody would like to, to speak on this particular topic?
Any questions that anybody might have?
Talk.
You gonna start running it with me?
No.
I'm running my book.
And if there are men, then you would close the public.
You'd like to get a golf cart, a troll.
All right.
So, if there's no other questions I won't mind, close the public hearing,
we'll go to line out of eight.
Action item submission of a grant application to the Oklahoma
Tourism and Recreation Aquarium Division of State Parks.
Motion.
I'll slide it.
Thank you.
All right.
Line out of eight.
Action.
Item resolution.
CC-2023-01, proclaiming an election for the mayor.
This is just stating that we are going to,
we're going to have an election in April.
Correct.
This is the official resolution that sets the filing dates,
with the broad dates, and the election dates.
It's all part of the process that we have to do with the election floor.
Any questions?
All right.
I'll second.
Senator.
Aye.
Thank you.
Be careful.
Aye.
Line out of ten.
Action item resolution.
CC-23-02.
It's part of my main street.
So this is a resolution that we are requesting from the council that would allow us to
present our applications, and better application to the Oklahoma Department of Commerce,
and specifically the Oklahoma Main Street.
center which would allow us to then start disfading in the Oklahoma Main Street program.
And I think we've talked about this a few times in the past and this is something
that we've actually included in our budget because part of our dissipation in the program
means that we have to commit a part-time resource to the program, which we have done in budget.
And we've got a position funded at 20 hours committed to that.
That will be working in the CVV under Amanda Davis.
This program is really going to help us with our Main Street.
And the resources that they provide is specifically kind of a teacher main to fish.
And they come down and they help with visioning, conduct volunteer and fund development workshop,
to provide technical visits to beach planning sessions and annual program assessments.
It also opens us up to greater opportunity for grant funding.
Most of the grants that we applied for the last couple years for Main Street,
we have recognized we did not get the grant, but they often go to Main Street programs.
And I think the reason that is and this shows more of a commitment in those communities,
when they are a member of the Main Street program,
they are committed to developing and redeveloping the Main Street.
And so this will get us in line with those communities and hopefully get us opportunities for that funding.
So this is simply the application and showing that we're committed in the Main Street requirements.
We'll need a job being able to put 20 hours in.
So primarily they'll work.
I think a lot of people downtown to work with the Department of Commerce, primarily.
So they'll be attending those trainings and then training others here locally.
They'll also work with the community and retail from Main Street.
And so it's a lot of planning and programming and creating for what I read about it.
It's about marketing and creating a vision for your community in downtown areas, specifically.
So it's making sure that we're tying all that together.
Should we do our festival or barbecue?
All of those things.
How does that work?
And do we over all picture of what we're trying to do to revitalize downtown?
How does it?
Some of all of that is part of that program getting everybody in the same page.
I know what we mean is really excited about it.
I'm been excited about it since I met with him.
You know, called the City of Conference and came back and started asking why.
My was in Dr. Spade in the back as we did participate in it for many years.
And then for whatever reason, I think we lost a resource.
And once they lost that resource, they basically the program and died off.
But it's definitely time that you get to engage with the state.
If I believe I'm right, I pay a call over.
I'm used to run that project.
And once you retired, I'll buy a ticket over.
I'm going to give that to my mouth.
That's right.
I'll try to put it before my time.
But yeah, I can see how I would have them.
But we do need to reengage.
We're going to have to be able to reform it to be higher.
At the same time, the person is going to be able to implement it.
So there can be somewhat fees at the pins of a level in which, and I think we're still
evaluating.
And that's why this resolution is somewhat open in there are multiple levels from what
I was reading on their website.
You can join is what they call a network.
Or you can be a fully designated program for an associate program.
And so we'll probably be applying early on with the least expensive program.
So we can get our tell-in-the-water and make sure we've got all of our ducks around and we're
going to fully align.
You're going to see the benefits from it.
But yeah, I think this really kind of sets us up for just the issue now.
And about currently, if I'm wrong, whenever we talk to this lady, didn't she say, whatever
there's current opportunities that we've applied for, they go look and see if we're a member
of this first.
Yeah.
I mean, yeah, she confirmed our report, but we were seeing they confirmed that it is definitely
part of which they're looking for commitment from it.
So it doesn't make sense.
So I'm not saying that we've missed grant opportunities because of this, but she did say that
was one of the first things they wouldn't look at.
So our community may get one before us, because they are coming in.
It's made to be a dumb question, what does FTE stand for?
Okay.
And we're calling a full-time employee for part-time.
And then in here, it says a new FTE has been approved in the current budget for 20 hours
a week.
So we budgeted for a full 40 hours a week, a person, but only part of it.
Oh, I got you.
Okay.
That makes sense.
So they're going to, they're going to do a back-to-sharing decision.
Okay.
I got you.
I don't know.
So I want to make sure I was clear on that.
Yeah.
Good question.
Any other questions?
Mike motion.
They're approved.
Second.
Right.
All right.
Number 11.
Any other business?
So if any which is a resistance opposing this agenda?
There's none.
Mayer and Kim, you can have some community announcements.
So I had some one approach or message me about it's kind of a funny thing and a lot of people don't
Realize I guess that we have day jobs, you know, that we we don't get paid for what we're doing or volunteers and so we work outside of here and about 40 hour week jobs, we'm score a family and I know at least one person had an issue with how I dressed and the fact that I work
And I'm okay with that the hats part of me so I'm going to continue where I have but
Because no me limits eliminate so we're going to talk about the business
And that's going to be five long math legs
Five long math legs is a new location in my am at 128 South Maine and the significance for this particular business because we have several that are in this way
It's happening right now in our community because they went from a least building to building they now
So they're investing in our community for the long term. They got a beautiful facility. I was in there today
Really nice of course you can't even work out while is there but
It's a beautiful facility and we appreciate the fact that they're investing in our community
There's going to be more of that same thing. There are local businesses that are going to be investing in buildings
So I'm going to talk about it once while with the hat and then we broadcast what they're doing and how they're doing
So I talked to Josh a little bit today and he said he appreciated the fact that we're going to talk about their business today
But he said it's really taking off. It's got a buzzroom community about their relocation
If you haven't stopped by, stop by and check it out. It's pretty cool
And I know the frozen elephant has went in there has a smoothie bar and stuff like that set up in there
So not only have they moved to an location got more space and but they've had features for people that will work out
So it's a nice facility
I would tell you I think to be in on Main Street with the glass products and drive by you snail sea glass front
You see people in there working out on treadmills and everything. I think it adds it's a great optics to our main street
Good host to that
Mayor have you made any new resolutions. I don't make them a little breaking
Any other announcements from council
On item 13 same manager communications
Nothing to add other than we had a fantastic year
Melinda has been putting together some notes and stuff
Kind of wrapping up in the year
We're going to take a look at the interview, I think scheduled tomorrow, KSN, and it wants to come talk with me, just kind of a recap of what we felt, you know, we accomplished over the last year.
It's a fantastic list.
It's going to be really exciting to get to share that and then be able to turn around and share that again next week.
That robbery.
I think Tuesday, Tuesday, I'll be speaking over again to share with them some of the highlights of our past year.
I think it's really great stuff, so once we get all of our notes together, kind of like finalized,
I'll share those with you all in our next week.
So kind of here when I'm getting to share it's fun, a lot of good stuff.
Thanks a lot.
All right.
14 adjournment.
Thank you.
All right.
1, 2, 1, 2, 3, 2, 3.
Not done.
Drive to get to see us.
We'll see you soon.
Thanks.
Thank you.